Welcome to another episode of news you
can use in which we'll be looking at
various stories and let me tell you
OpenAI has been releasing things that we
haven't seen before on mass this week.
So that's kind of the main story of this
week between Sora 2 and the brand new
social media platform that goes along
with it. Yes, that's a thing or the chat
pulse release where it proactively sends
you notifications or Google's AI image
editing being integrated left and right.
We have so many things to discuss and
demo in this week's episode of News You
Can Use, the show that rounds up all the
AI releases, filters for the ones that
matter, and then I get to present them
back to you, including demos,
comparisons, all the good stuff that we
like to do on this channel. So, let's
begin by talking about Sora, cuz this is
really the big story of the week.
There's a few parts to this. I want to
start by saying that this caused a
massive wave on all social media
channels. On Instagram, people are going
crazy and showing off all sorts of memes
and use cases as if this was the first
good AI video model ever. Which first
got me thinking, hey, this is not that
big of a deal. Like, haven't you seen
the Chinese models? Haven't you seen V3?
But then you dig deeper and quickly
realize that the unique selling
proposition is not the fact that this is
on par with some of the best models out
there. I would even say the audio is
arguably better than the one of V3.
>> Cannon bottle.
That's cold. The unique selling
proposition of this is the fact that
they shipped it in a standalone
application only on iOS for now, only in
US. But that application acts sort of as
a Tik Tok clone that only includes AI
generated content with one standout
feature. And that feature they call
Cameo. It's essentially where you record
your voice sample and a video sample of
yourself and it creates an AI cameo aka
avatar of yourself that then you or
other users can use to generate anything
with your permission of course. I mean
this is sort of a privacy nightmare to
be honest because like you're literally
cloning yourself and making that
available on a social media platform.
But yeah, this is happening and not just
that you can create things with your own
cameo, you can also use other users
cameos and use multiple have them
interact and what they created here I
think is really impressive and is a
first in the AI space. But we've been
hearing and talking about a AI powered
social media platform from OpenAI for a
while now and this is it. It's a AI
native Tik Tok which understandably
raises a lot of concerns but let's look
at some of the examples here for you to
get a bit of a feeling of what's going
on. And ultimately, I would actually
really recommend watching the live
stream they did here. It's 20 minutes
and it's probably the best live stream
they have held yet in my opinion. It
answers all the questions that I had and
the demos are fantastic. It shows you
the different functionalities. It shows
you the ability to remix existing videos
with your likeness. It shows you the
ability to add different object or remix
pretty much everything on the feed with
text prompts and your cameos. So, you
can insert yourself into any video. You
can dance battle with your friends,
whatever it might be. I just think this
is a really good interface and this is
something that was already true for Sora
1. The one thing I mentioned on Sora
launch was that hey the application
actually has the most userfriendly
interface. They really got that right
but the model at that point was just not
that special anymore. So as you can see
from some of these examples they use Sam
Alman's likeness with a custom prompt to
generate these videos. And one thing
that I want to highlight here which was
not immediately obvious to me is that
these videos are actually edited too. It
doesn't just generate clips as you could
up until now. It actually edits the
thing. It cuts in. It cuts out. The
sound remains consistent. There's music
in the background that plays throughout
it. There's sound effects. It's just
like your experience on Instagram reels,
YouTube shorts, or Tik Tok, but all
created by AI. So, news flash, I
actually managed to get access to Sora.
The codes have been quite widely
available. And I want to start off by
actually giving you a code and proposing
something. Look, it's first come, first
serve. And if you get this code and use
it, what you can do is you can go down
here and say invite friends in the
interface. and then you can leave a
comment below or reply to another code
and share one of your codes. This way,
theoretically, if everybody does this,
we should be able to get every viewer of
the YouTube video into Sora. If you're
feeling generous, you can copy two codes
and we can keep this going. Anyway, now
that I'm in, I'm able to generate videos
and use all of the different cameos of
the other people. So, right off the bat,
I did what I always do. And I should
point out the site is very laggy at this
point in time. I think it's just getting
a lot of usage. And then if I look at my
first generation, of course it was,
>> "Hey, handsome, looking cozy in your new
hat. You like it?"
>> A cat with a hat. And then I wanted to
try the cameo feature. So I used Sam
Alman's cameo and said, "Walking a cat
with a hat." And I got this.
>> This is her little hat. She actually
likes it. See, she doesn't mind it at
all.
>> And now here's the interesting thing.
Whenever you create a new one, you have
all these different cameos. And you
could also switch to Sora 2 Pro. The
difference between Sora 2 and Sora 2 Pro
is subtle, but it does make a
difference.
>> No, no, no. Dodge, you pixelated
pretzel. Roll you medieval idiot.
>> He's still swinging for the play by
swinging. Come on. Roll you tin can
roll. Who designed this? He's winding
up. He's winding up. I
>> see himorty. I see it. I was
>> It's a bit sharper. Audio sounds the
same. But ultimately, the most
interesting thing in here, I think, is
the fact that you can create your own
cameos. And this is something I
unfortunately have not been able to do
as of yet because you need a few things
to access the cameos. First of all, you
need a OpenAI account. And then you need
to be using a VPN and an invite code to
even use Sora. These are the free
prerequisites. But even if you have
that, in order to create your own Cameo,
you need the mobile app. And in order to
get the mobile app, you need to set your
iPhone to the US location and have a US
Apple ID. And I did some research and
the best way to do that is to get an
extra phone. So I will be doing that
over the course of the next week. So for
future videos, I can test all of these
applications for you. And I guess next
week, I'll be sharing my own Cameo with
you. As of now, enjoy some of the invite
codes. They're becoming quite widely
spread. And then I just want to say that
this feed is actually unbelievably
entertaining, way more so than I
initially expected because the
restrictions are very low. You have all
of this well-known IP like Pokemon and
Spongebob and all of it just works super
well. People are remixing it and my for
you page is already becoming better than
it was in the first minutes and it's
just super entertaining. So there you
go. If you can go try it for yourself
and more next week, but for now let's
look at some of the other OpenAI
releases which are again firsts in their
category. One of them being chat GPT
pulse, a new feature that proactively
sends you notifications. Now, actually
turning this on if you're on a pro
account. Again, this is just gated to
the $200 plan is not obvious. It took me
multiple minutes to actually find it,
but it's only available on the mobile
app. You have to go into your settings,
then notifications, and there you can
find the pulse updates, which you need
to switch on. And then also, I should
note on the personalization, there's
this new pulse setting where you can use
your memories with the pulse, which also
requires this reference chat history to
be enabled. And then if you have all of
this on only then will pulse work. And
then this took me a while to figure out.
So I guess I'll have to wait for my
first pulse because each day I sort of
turned one of these things on and then I
also had chaty notifications off. So
I'll follow up next week with my first
pulse. Next thing that OpenAI introduces
and again this is a first. So this is
really the theme of this week are
parental controls. This is not something
that's available inside of Enthropics
Claude or Google's Gemini or any other
AI model. I mean forget about the
Chinese one having parental control. The
only control those have is the
government overlooking all the data.
Little stab right there, but hey, I
think that's fair enough. But yeah, this
is coming to Chat GPT and parents will
be able to limit the content that their
children can generate with Chat GPT,
including essential controls like
removing sensitive content or even
disabling things like image generation
or saved memories. Eventually, the best
version of these apps will be the
unlocked one where adults can access the
full range of thoughts of an adult human
being. I like this base principle of
everything that is legal within our
society also being legal within AI
tools. And obviously you need a
separation between minors and adults.
And this feature is available as of
today for all church users. You just
have to go under parental controls. Then
you can add family members, invite them
via email, and then set up the controls
in here. If you're a mom or a dad, might
not be the worst idea to do this. And
then one more thing out of OpenAI and
we'll just quickly brush over this but I
thought it was extremely interesting
because they introduced a new benchmark
that evaluates different AI models on
how much value they can create in GDP
relevant tasks. In other words, on tasks
that are actually performed in the real
world and that create real value in
society. And I always like reading these
practical papers, but what really stood
out to me is the fact that in their own
paper, it clearly shows that Claude Opus
4.1 performs way better than all the
chat GPT models on real world tasks.
Matter of fact, this is one of the big
graphs in here. This red line is what
would be rated as the performance of an
industry expert. And you can clearly see
Opus 4.1 being the closest to that line.
And it doesn't even include the new
Sonnet 4.5 release from this week that
we'll talk about in a second here. And I
also created a separate video on it this
week. But as you can see, it really sets
Enthropic apart here. And in the
appendex of this paper, you can see the
detailed breakdown. I mean, this paper
is only looking at 1,320 tasks across 44
different occupations, but here you have
a breakdown by sector. So for real
estate and rentals and leasing tasks,
Claude crushes it and is essentially
almost at the human baseline. And I
agree with this with these sales and
transaction related tasks. Claude is so
damn good. It sounds more human. The
analysis is more useful. It's more
concise and to the point. And for retail
related tasks, you can see it even beats
the human baseline. If it just comes to
providing information, GPT5 high
actually gets the closest. And if you
want to learn more about the details,
you can pause the video right here and
have a closer look at some of these. So,
as you can see, for industrial
engineers, it doesn't get even close.
But for shipping, receiving, and
inventory clerks, multiple models
perform better than the human baseline.
Software developers is another one that
ranks high. And again, this data set
will not be perfect. Nevertheless, I
think this is a good indicator to see in
which lines of work AI is going to have
the biggest impact in the close future
versus jobs like film and video editors
or audio and visual technicians only
getting a little bit of help. Financial
managers are another one whereas cloth
gets really close and that's because
it's so damn good at working with Excel
sheets at this point I think. And also
my last note on this is I think that
makes up a lot of the data because the
paper also shows that a bulk of these
tasks is actually work inside of Excel
sheets, PowerPoint presentations or PDFs
which is Claude is exceptional at and
that's why it scores so high. If it's
pure text or other tasks actually GPT5
high goes toe-to-toe with claude in pure
text, GPT5 being way better actually. So
yeah, very interesting stuff. Hope you
found this equally as interesting as I
did. And then super quickly, another new
thing out of OpenAI.
>> This mother don't miss
>> is an instant checkout feature. So we
had CHP shopping before where you could
buy things from within Chacht, but it
would redirect you to their site and you
buy it there. Now starting with Etsy,
there's a direct checkout feature within
Chachet. It's US only and Etsy only for
now. But for the very first time, you
don't have to leave Chat GPT to make the
transaction. And I guess if you play
this out, all of your shopping would be
done directly from within Chat GPT. And
eventually AI would even make the
decision on buying things cuz it would
know your needs better than you do.
That's far off in the future. This show
is here to talk about what's possible
today most of the times. Okay. So
recently I've been using this new AI
tool called Warp Code. It's very similar
to a classic IDE which is the default
code editing environment that developers
use to build applications, but it's
built with AI and agentic capabilities
in mind from the ground up rather than
slapping them on top of an existing
platform. If you follow the channel
closely, you might have seen a full
tutorial showing you the workflow inside
of Warp. And I recommend you check that
video out if this interests you. But I
wanted to quickly show off one more
feature that didn't make it into that
video, and that's using MCPS within
Warp. Also, a huge thank you to Warp for
sponsoring this video and making our
productions possible. So, if you've been
following the channel for a while,
you'll be aware that I'm a huge fan of
open protocols and especially MCPs,
which if you were living in a cave and
are still not aware of what that means,
it's model context protocol and it's
basically the standard way of how to
connect tools to agents. And you can do
exactly that inside of Warp Code. So, as
you develop and as you build your
application out, you can connect to an
external data source with an MCP. Let me
show you what that looks like in
practice. All you need to do is head on
over to your settings inside of Warp and
then under AI, if you scroll down,
you're going to see this MCP section
here, manage MCP servers. And in here, I
can simply click add. For example, for
the context 7 API key, I did the
following. I would enter this code, link
my API key from my logged in Context 7
account. Now, if I start a new project,
I can access all the documentation in
the world through context 7 because it's
connected already.
And there it is. It's using the MCP tool
to pull in the documentation. If you
wonder how to set up MCP servers and you
feel a little lost, well, I would
actually recommend heading over to the
warp documentation here and then copying
this entire documentation into a brand
new Chat GPT thread and then doing the
same thing for any MCP server that you
might be interested in like this context
7 MCP on GitHub. Same thing. You just
add all of this context into the
conversation and chat will guide you for
exactly what you need to set this up.
And that would be an easy way to access
all the up-to-ate documentation in the
world through the context 7 MCP. And
there you go. Now, warp code can pull
info directly from that source. And I
don't have to constantly manage the
context manually. And that's just one of
many amazing features inside of Warp. If
this segment interested you, make sure
to check out the full video to see how
the workflow looks like. There's just
many little optimizations that add up
and developers report that they save 5
hours per week just by using this app.
And for a limited time only, they're
giving away their premium pro plan for
$5 per month. Head on over to the link
at the top of the video description and
use the code advantage to redeem that
offer and get started with Warp today.
All right, and now let's have a look at
the next piece of AI news that you can
use. Next up, I want to talk about all
the Claude releases this week. And if
you follow the channel closely, I
created a separate 30 minute long video
showing off what I think is the biggest
feature in here, which is their browser
extension. And I'm not going to go deep
into that because that's what that video
is for. I showed you like four or five
different workflows, step by step, and
results that you can achieve with this.
It's been a few days and I still stand
by this being the biggest innovation in
AI for me and my work since deep
research. I think it's that good. And I
think the biggest thing that I would
point out about it now that I didn't
mention in the video is the fact that it
can reliably execute the task that you
give it. There's just less variance. Not
saying it's perfect, it's just more
consistent. But the new extension is
only one of multiple releases, and I
really didn't show you any of the others
cuz I thought this one was so
significant that I wanted to spend all
the time on it. If you didn't see that
video and you enjoy the show, I highly
recommend you check the video out. It
really shows the capability of this and
where I think the AI space is going
next, which is these browser agents that
have the ability to fetch context for
you rather than you really having to
know what to give it and then manually
providing it to. But there were other
releases, too. Obviously, there was the
4.5 model release which you know we can
just quickly talk about and say that
it's pretty much state-of-the-art at
most benchmarks especially on coding and
as I highlighted on these computer use
tasks which are real world tasks that
human actually perform with computers.
It is head and shoulders above
everything else. So it's a really great
model but we hear that a lot these days.
The kind of vibes on it as people would
call it are very positive. A lot of
people absolutely love this and a lot of
people I know that switched from clot
code to codeex now switched back to clot
code because clot code also got a bit of
an update and this I also want to show
you. So if I just open up clot code in
my terminal you will see it has a new
interface and this is essentially clot
code 2.0 cuz it has so many new
features. I think most significantly
they have now checkpoints built in.
Before you needed to use GitHub to
arrive at a previous version, but now it
has it built in. And also the default
model is Sonnet 4.5. They don't have
this opus for planning mode that I
recommended in my what was it 70 80
minute long clawed code beginner
tutorial. I guess the only thing that
changed since then is you just keep this
on default because Sonnet 4.5 works so
well. Then there's also this new context
command which shows you the context
usage visually which I really love
because a part of cloud code that is
important is not hitting this context
unexpectedly because often it compacts
things away that you might not want to
compact away. So this is a welcome
addition and additionally there's also
this new feature. It's not really a
release but it is something that has
been really missing. Clot.ai/s settings/
usage and this allows you to track your
cla account usage across all of the
things that link to your account. So
that would be their web interface,
Claude.AI, it would be Claude Code,
which is their CLI agent, and now even
the new browser extension that remote
controls your browser. All three of
these are paid through your account and
therefore account for these usage
limits. And before you didn't really
know where you're at, you kind of just
got locked out at a certain point and
had to wait for a few hours. Now you can
finally track this here. Which leaves us
with one more thing from this release
that I really wanted to highlight here
in this show. And that is this fun
little interface that most people
probably don't have access to because
it's only accessible to the $200 max
plan. And I don't think this really has
a specific use case or I wouldn't even
like recommend it, but I think it's a
wonderful thing to demo in this show
because this is sort of like a virtual
computer interface wise. And you can
really think of this as anthropics
artifacts in this brand new more
friendly interface with more sounds and
more visuals. In case you're not
familiar with artifacts, it's whenever
you create a app within Claude, which is
a chat competitor rather than just
giving you the code. What an artifact is
is turning that code into an actually
usable application right in your
browser. So you can see it writes the
code here and would open up over here is
the artifact where I can actually press
the buttons and see how this works
rather than just getting the raw code.
And rather than me describing what this
is, I'll just show you. You can pick one
of these presets or custom prompt and
it's going to start building this
interface step by step. And the big
claim they make here is that none of
these uses predefined code and it just
in a very free form manner is going to
build your application step by step. And
as it builds it, it also shows it. So
this is really more like a stream of
consciousness from the AI to your little
claude imagine desktop. And I suppose
you could use this really well for some
brainstorming workflows which I always
love. And also them claiming that this
is more free form and always uses
different code kind of implies that
artifacts and Claude uses certain boiler
plates and certain presets which I
wasn't fully aware of. But yeah, there
you go. The choose your own adventure
game. I'm not going to read all of this
but I see you quit your job at big corp.
You have some savings. You have an idea
and then there's free notifications.
former college roommate offers to
invest. YC wants you and there's a
potential co-founder. What's your first
move? I say we just bootstrap and
monetize here. And then you can see that
it notices what I clicked and it
develops the rest of the app afterwards.
So it updates the runway, etc. And there
you go. We have five paying customers
with 2.4K MR. And it gives me new
choices. And it's building all of this
as I'm moving through it while showing
me the context. 29K out of 100K tokens
used. And now we keep moving. So very
similar to artifacts, but this is not
sharable externally and it's way more
free form. You can create any kind of
interface for you and you can alter it
as you go. Whereas artifacts sort of
create something and then you can extend
that. But really this has more of a
consistent memory which is also using
some of the new releases which include a
memory function in the API. Now there's
like a whole API SDK if you're a
developer that you should look into. And
yeah, there you go. That's everything
new out of anthropic this week. Some
really interesting and innovative stuff.
Again, the big highlight for me being
the browser extension that actually
works and can be relied upon. Okay, so
for the next story, we have something
interesting. It's Lovable, which you
might already know as one of the best no
code builders to actually get started
with, and they made a massive massive
update. And the update essentially
simplifies the process of using it for
everyone. It's called Lovable Cloud, and
it basically allows you to do certain
things like integrating a database
without actually creating a database and
setting up a separate account. So up
until now the way most of these no code
builders worked is you build an app
inside of them and that links to an
external database that stores things
like user login etc. Now they merge this
into one thing. So we're going to give
this a free shot and the wonderful thing
here is it actually works on a free plan
and this also includes AI integrations.
So no need to link to your openi key.
You can kind of just do things right in
here. So I'm just going to do something
simple like build a pomodoro timer app
with authentication. And as you can see,
if I launch this, there's no button here
to connect to Sappa basease or something
because all of that is built in. Now,
seriously, this is quite a big step. And
we've partnered with most of these
companies that do these sort of things
on this channel, as you might know. And
this was a big tripwire for a lot of
people coming into it like what is a SQL
database? Why do I have to create this
separate account? I just want to build
app. And there it is. After a bit of
time, we have our application. And you
can see it has authentication right
away. And as I create account and log in
right away, I have this working Pomodoro
timer in here. And I did not need to
connect a supper account to store that
user information. It just works. There's
built-in analytics too now. And yeah,
when I go to this cloud tab, I can see
the database it created. We have
profiles which are the users. We have
the different Pomodoro timer session
timer settings. You can see the user
that I just created right here in this
database view. And it's all in here. And
that also includes all the AI
connections. So no need to fetch API
keys anymore. It's all sort of just
included in your subscription here,
which is really cool. And it makes it so
much more beginner friendly. Next up,
this will be quick, but it's just a
technique on how to create corporate
looking head shot with Nano Banana from
any images you might have of yourself or
others. And Google shared this
themselves. It's this prompt right here
that I'll put in the description of this
video. You just put this into Gemini,
upload that image of yourself, quick
screenshot of me, paste it in here, and
let's see what we get. That's kind of
good. There you go. Prompt in the
description, and have fun. Next up, we
have news in Photoshop, which I
personally always love to see cuz as you
might know, it was the very first
software I learned back in high school
and that was sort of the beginning of my
software journey, which led me all the
way to here 15 years later. But what
they did now is they integrated some of
the most popular AI image editing models
into Photoshop. So, they're not just
sticking to their own models, but really
taking some of the state-of-the-art
models like Nano Banana or Flux Context
and integrating them here. So, logged in
for my Adobe subscription. You can see
right away that this is the feature
we're talking about. You can use
Nanabanana and Flux Context Pro in here
and even use them with these features
like harmonize. So, let's just give this
a quick shot. So, let me just take this
random thumbnail I had lying around.
Sure. Scale it up a little. Duplicate
it. Oh god, they changed some of the
stuff around. And then what I'm going to
do is replace this phone with something
else. So, here I should be able to
generate a fill. And then here, ah, here
I can switch the model. So, I'm going to
go to Nana Banana and I'm going to say
change the phone into a microphone. And
as you might know, if you haven't been
living under a rock over the past few
months, Nano Banana is just really good
at these editing operations. You know
what? Let's give it another try cuz this
is okay, but not great. I guess it just
didn't understand that. Yeah. Okay, this
is what I was actually looking for. So,
that's really good. Now, we can go ahead
and switch the model and see what we in
comparison get with the Adobe model.
Let's give it the same edit. So, as you
can see, this is not it. It's not just
that the image quality of the mic is
worse. It also kind of was way too
creative here. I sort of like the idea
of this lady singing at me while being
at sea, but it didn't understand the
prompt as equally as it didn't hear. So,
we're going to do the same thing one
more time, but with Flux Context Pro,
and then you're going to have a nice
little comparison of all three models in
action here. Flux Context Pro. Yeah,
this just didn't work. Nano Banana
nailed this on a second try and that's
why people consider it the best. And now
with the power of this inside of
Photoshop, it's a whole new application.
Honestly, a lot of people say that these
models sort of replace Photoshop, but I
think knowing Photoshop and knowing
these models, that's the real winning
combination cuz you can do everything
you could have done in Photoshop, but
also use the power of AI and just
combine them. And in this week's quick
hits, there's really two stories I want
to highlight. The first one is a
follow-up to last week's story where the
first artist was getting signed for
millions of dollars for nothing but AI
music with really good lyrics. And this
week's follow-up story is this lady
called Thy Norwood, which is the first
AI actress. And it's sort of interesting
to see how much backlash this story is
getting versus the singer not being
faced with the same sort of public
scrutiny. Apparently, she's in
negotiation with multiple Hollywood
talent firms. And this is just a thing
that's happening now. AI celebrities
going mainstream. The other quick hit
that I want to highlight here, and I
think this is a really good one to end
on, is the so-called rise of AI
generated work slop. And I watched this
Atriarch video on it which puts it
really well. And there's this really
good quote on what that actually means.
And I absolutely absolutely love this.
So listen closely. This would be the
definition of it. AI generated work
content that masquerades as good work
but lacks the substance to meaningfully
advance a given task. So it's something
that looks good but isn't able to move a
project forward. I see this all the time
and this is the biggest risk with AI and
I think it happens if you don't provide
sufficient context. If you write up a
report and you use AI to edit it, great.
It's so helpful. But if you really think
that you're going to come in with a
blank canvas and in a short prompt
you're going to create something that a
human would work on for 3 days, all
you're doing is pushing the work that
you're supposed to be doing to another
person. And whether you're a manager, an
employee, a soloreneur, a CEO, this is
something to become aware of in these
days. People are using these tools, but
that doesn't mean they're doing good
work. It allows the lazy to masquerade
as productive members of the team. And
it gives them the ability to push off
work to others. And we all collectively
should become less tolerant of this and
recognize some of these AI generations
for what they are, which are different
tools to enhance your work, but not to
replace it. We're not there quite yet,
so use everything you learned on this
show wisely. All right, and that's
pretty much everything we have for this
week. I hope you found some of this
interesting. I would be super curious to
hear in the comments if you experience
some of this AI work slop in your own
workplace or company or frankly if
you're guilty of this too. I know it's
really easy to fall into this but some
people just seem to be doing this all
the time which yeah is a problem. Either
way, my name is Igor and I hope you have
a wonderful